https://recipes.net/privacy-policy/

Recipes For Newbies
It’s A Steak Out!
Its Time To Barbeque!
Articles: Cooking Tips & Guides
Recipe of the Day
VIEW ALL CATEGORIES
HomePrivacy Policy
Privacy PolicyWho We Are?Our website address is: https://recipes.net and we are your one-stop-shop for all things cooking. Our platform allows users to create and share their favorite recipes. What Personal Data We Collect & Why?1) CommentsWhen visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form. Additionally, the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string is collected to help with spam detection.An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it.The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.2) MediaIf you upload images to the website, it is advised that you avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. If you do, visitors to the website are able t download and extract any location data from images on the website.3) Contact formsInformation provided to us under the ‘contact forms’ is saved and stored in our database. This allows us to better cater to the demographics of our users and members. In other words, by knowing who you are, we can focus on creating content that you will better enjoy. 4) CookiesIf you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website as cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again should you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.If you visit our login page, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded once you close your browser.When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. Should you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, these login cookies will be removed.If you edit or publish a recipe, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.5) Embedded content from other websitesArticles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behave in the exact same way as if, you, the visitor had visited the supporting website.These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.6) AnalyticsOur website collects data for the purpose of analytics. Similar to what we had mentioned with regards to contact forms, analytics help us cater to our target audience. In other words, it helps us make the site work for you in the best way possible. Who We Share Your Data With? Any information collected here on our website is not shared with any third parties without your consent. Information that we garner is used solely for the aforementioned reasons, primarily, your convenience in terms of logging in and analytics for our team. How Long Do We Retain Your Data?If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (with the exception of changing their username). Website administrators are also at liberty to see and edit that information.What Rights Do You Have Over Your Data? If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold revolving around your account, including any data you have provided to us.You may also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.Where Do We Send Your Data?Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. However, we do not send your personal information to any other third party sites without your consent. The only time your personal information may be shared is when required by law. Do You Have Questions About Our Privacy Policy?Should you have any further questions, do not hesitate to reach out to us – we will gladly clear any queries you might be facing. Please feel free to drop us an email @ contact@recipes.net
We use cookies on this website to enhance our site and your user experience. Please refer to the section on Cookies within our Privacy Policy for more information.
Allow Cookies
Recipes.net Push Notifiction ConsentDon't miss out!We would like to send you notifications of the best and newest recipes. No Thanks Allow Share Your Recipes!Share Your Recipes!Want to share your own special recipe? Simply register with us and start sharing! Submit Recipes No Thanks
Close GDPR Cookie Settings
Privacy Overview
Strictly Necessary Cookies
Privacy OverviewWe use cookies to collect information about how you interact with our website and allow us to remember you. This information is collected to remember your preferences so as to personalize your browsing experience. It is also used for analytics and metrics about our visitors on this website in a way that does not directly identify individuals. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our Privacy Policy.
Strictly Necessary CookiesStrictly Necessary Cookie should be enabled at all times so that we can save your preferences for cookie settings.
Enable or Disable Cookies
If you disable this cookie, we will not be able to save your preferences. This means that every time you visit this website you will need to enable or disable cookies again.
Enable All Save Changes
